Emmanuel Charon

emmanuel.charon@outlook.com, +33 6 80 92 91 05, Paris, France.

PROFILE

I am a battle-proven project manager and lead programmer with experience in startup environments. I have a passion for solving hard problems which require creativity. My double expertise is in applied machine learning and video game development. I live for the opportunity to apply my skills for the greater good.

SKILLS

Creativity, machine learning, programming, cloud computing, project management, game design, game development, user experience, data analytics, web data mining.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jun 2017 - present Machine Learning R&D Engineer at AODocs in Paris. Created ML applications in the product.

Jul 2015 - Jun 2017 Founder of Irminsul Studio in Paris. Invented, produced and published video games.

Apr 2013 - Jul 2015 Machine Learning Engineer at Diffbot in California. Designed, coded, tested, and improved state-of-

the-art AI algorithms to analyse web pages automatically using supervised machine learning.

Sep 2012 - Apr 2013 Teaching Assistant at Stanford University in California, in computer networking classes.

Summer 2012 Software Engineer Intern at Cisco Systems in San Jose, California. Worked on a datacenter OS.

Spring 2011 Research Intern in Applied Mathematics at Telecom ParisTech in Paris. Worked on network

congestion control and received a prize.

Summer 2010 Waiter at the Hotel Las Brisas, Acapulco, Mexico. Summer job in a luxury hotel.

Sep 2008 - Apr 2009 Police Officer at Gendarmerie Nationale in Caen, France. Military internship in an intelligence

agency.

EDUCATION

Sep 2011 - Apr 2013 Master of Science at Stanford University in California, in Electrical Engineering. Coursework on

computer networks, data analysis and machine learning.

Sep 2008 - Aug 2011 Diplôme d'Ingénieur at École Polytechnique, in Palaiseau, France. Coursework on mathematics,

programming and telecommunication protocols.

Sep 2006 - Aug 2008 Classes Préparatoires at Lycée Louis Le Grand in Paris, France. Preparatory years for the nationwide

competitive examination for scientific studies.

LINKS

LinkedIn - full resume: https://www.linkedin.com/in/emmanuel-charon-03725357/

GitHub: https://github.com/emmanuelcharon

Irminsul website: http://www.irminsul.studio/

LANGUAGES, TECHNOLOGIES AND HOBBIES

Languages: French, English.

Programming languages: Java, Python, C#, JavaScript, C++.

Cloud Computing: Google Compute Platform, Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure.

Game Development: Unity3D.

Hobbies: Game Jams, Ecology, Running, Snowboard, Cooking, Playing Football.